NATE GRIGG

nate@nategrigg.com

+1 801 599 NATE

With 20 years of experience, Nate has an intuitive creativity that is hard to come by in engineers. Combine this creativity with an uncanny knack for abstraction and you get ingenious technical solutions. Mix in Nate's natural aversion to inefficiency and you end up with truly elegant systems designs.

WORK HISTORY

Senior Software Engineer, ReliaQuest

August 2021 – March 2022

"Squad Lead" for a team of front-end and back-end developers.

Ported an internal application into ReliaQuest's customer-facing application "GreyMatter".

JAVA microservices built with SPRING BOOT, SPRING MVC, and POSTGRESQL (deployed to AWS).

Principal Software Engineer, Newfold Digital / Bluehost Dec 2019–July 2021

Tech Lead on a team with 4 fellow developers. Built and inherited 3 microservices

PYTHON, DJANGO, FLASK, MICROSERVICES, JSON WEB TOKENS (JWT)

MAGiE, a Personal Project (Mobile Puzzle Game)

Nov 2018-Oct 2019

magiegame.com

Built a mobile puzzle game about BINARY ENCODING.

C# 7, .NET CORE on Mac, NUGET, COMPONENT-ORIENTED DESIGN, IOS APP STORE, GOOGLE PLAY STORE

Senior Software Engineer, Ancestry Inc.

Apr 2015-Dec 2018

JAVA 8, MAVEN, JUNIT, JAX-RS, AWS, REST, MICROSERVICES, (Including breaking up a monolith), REFACTORING, AUTOMATED TESTING, JENKINS, SCRUM

Senior Software Engineer, Intermountain Healthcare

Mar 2014-Apr 2015

Senior Software Engineer, RedBell Real Estate

Sep 2013-Feb 2014

Consultant → Senior Consultant, Application Development, Avanade Inc.

Software Engineer in Test, Control4

2004-2006May 2006-Sep 2013

Software Developer, ThoughtLab

2002-2004

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science University of Utah

2002-2006